=Hot Blooded=
= المدونة الساخنة =
=Episode 5=
= الحلقة 5 =
I owe you my life.
أنا أدين لك بحياتي
Today,
اليوم
I'll give it back to you.
سأعيدها إليك
Then we'll be even.
إذن سنظل متعادلين
- No! - Mother!
- لا! - أمي!
- Xiruo!
- شيرو!
Mother!
أمي!
Uncle Yang!
العم يانغ!
Senior!
أقدم!
Mother!
أمي!
Senior, are you okay?
هل أنت بخير يا سيدي؟
Jing,
جينغ
your father and I
أنا وأبوك
made a pact long ago.
منذ فترة طويلة
If we had a boy and a girl,
إذا كان لدينا فتى وفتاة
they'd be a married couple.
لكانا زوجين
I have no daughter.
لا لديّ ابنة
- Father... - I cherish
- أبي... - أنا أعتز
my adopted daughter like my own.
ابنتي المعتمدة مثل ابنتي
Father.
أبي
- I'll take care of it. - Father.
- سأهتم بها - أبي
Brother Yang,
الأخ يانغ
don't worry.
لا تقلق
Friends,
أصدقاء
thanks for bringing about this marriage.
شكرا على تحقيق هذا الزواج
I can
أنا يمكنني
die in peace now.
أن أموت في سلام الآن
Father...
أبي
Uncle Yang.
العم يانغ
Xiruo.
شيرو يو
Tiexin.
تيexين
Although it is
على الرغم من أنه
18 years late,
بعد 18 سنة
we're finally together.
نحن أخيرا معا
Enough.
كفي
Mother!
أمي!
- Uncle Yang! - Father!
- العم يانغ! - أبي!
Mother!
أمي!
Your Royal Highness.
صاحب السمو الملكي
Everything is fated.
كل شيء مقدح
Let them be.
دعهما وشأنها
Come and get me.
تعال وأستطيع
- Your Highness. - What are you doing?
- صاحب السمو - ماذا تفعل؟
Your Highness, watch out!
صاحب السمو، احترسي!
Give me Taoist Qiu's antidote,
أعطني الترياق تشيو مضاد
- or I'll kill him! - You dare?
- أو سأقتله! - هل تجرؤ؟
You forced my parents to death,
لقد أجبرت والديّ على الموت
why wouldn't I dare?
لماذا لا أجرؤ؟
Stop.
توقف
I'll give it to you.
سأعطيها لك
Here it is. Here it is.
ها هي ذا
I never thought you righteous school
لم أكن أعتقد أنكم المدرسة الصالحة
would resort to threats.
ستلجأ إلى التهديدات
And you're not above
ولست فوق
using poison, are you?
باستخدام السم، أليس كذلك؟
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
You are all renowned figures
أنتم جميعا شخصيات مشهورة
in the martial world.
في عالم القتال
We're evenly matched today.
نحن متساويان اليوم
How about we set another date?
ماذا عن أن نضع تاريخا آخر؟
We can
يمكننا
have a proper contest then.
أن نتنافس إذن
That would be best.
سيكون هذا أفضل
What do you propose?
ماذا تقترح؟
Half a year later,
بعد نصف عام
on Mid-Autumn Festival,
في مهرجان منتصف الخريف
at Zuixian Restaurant, South Lake, Jiaxing,
في مطعم زويشيان، جنوب بحيرة جيازينغ
we'll admire the moon
سنعجب باستخدام القمر
and test our skills.
واختبار مهاراتنا
Do you dare come?
هل تجرؤ على المجيء؟
Why wouldn't we?
لماذا لا نأتي؟
Fine.
حسنا
We Seven Immortals of Quanzhen
نحن سبعة خيال من كوانزين
will surely be there.
بالتأكيد سيكون هناك
On our Seven Freaks of Jiangnan's turf,
على أسطح جيانغنان السبعة
you should bring more people.
يجب أن تحضر المزيد من الناس
Or don't say we bullied you then.
أو لا تقل إننا تنمروا عليك إذن
Alright.
حسنًا
That's a deal.
لكن
Miss Mu,
الآنسة مو
how did your father live
كيف عيش والدك
these past years?
في هذه السنوات الماضية؟
Over the past ten years,
على مدى السنوات العشر الماضية
my father took me all over.
أخذني والدي كل شيء
We never stayed anywhere
لم نبق في أي مكان
for longer than half a month.
لأكثر من نصف شهر
He said
قال
we should find a man named Guo.
يجب أن نجد رجلا يُدعى غاو
Mr. Ke,
السيد كي
your apprentice
تلميذك
has a noble heart.
لديه قلب نبيل
But my apprentice...
لكن تلميذي...
Stop!
توقف!
Get out.
اخرج
Master,
معلمي
please let me light incense
من فضلك دعني أنور الخور
for my mother.
لأمي
You, a traitorous prince of Jin,
أنت، أمير خائن من جين
bullying your master and betraying your ancestors,
وتتنمر على معلمك وتخون أسلافك
how dare you
كيف تجرؤ
offer incense
يعرض البخور
to the loyal Yang couple.
لثنائي يانغ المخلصين
I only want to offer incense to my mother.
أريد فقط أن أقدم البخور لأمي
You really think I won't kill you?
هل تعتقد حقا أنني لن أقتلك؟
Jing, what are you doing?
جينغ، ماذا تفعل؟
(Bao Xiruo's Spirit Tablet)
(لوحة روح باي شيرو)
Jing, let go.
جينغ، اتركني
Taoist Qiu,
تاي تشيو
please calm down.
اهدأ من فضلك
He's done much wrong!
لقد ارتكب الكثير من الخطأ!
Even so,
ومع ذلك
he's Uncle Yang's only child.
إنه طفل عمه يانغ الوحيد
Fine.
حسنا
I won't kill him today.
لن أقتله اليوم
This brat
هذا الشقي
still doesn't admit that his surname is Yang!
لا يعترف بأن لقبه يانغ!
I've borne the name Wanyan for 18 years.
لقد حملت اسم وان يان لمدة 18 عاما
None of you have told me
لم يخبرني أحد منكم
Yang Tiexin is my father!
يانغ تيهشين هو والدي!
Now you say I'm Yang,
الآن تقولين إنني يانغ
a Han Chinese.
هان صيني
Why should I believe you?
لماذا يجب أن أصدقك؟
Why?
لماذا؟
Jing,
جينغ
is your hand alright?
هل يدك بخير؟
This rascal!
هذا الوغد!
He's not worth it.
إنه لا يستحق كل هذا العناء
Master,
معلمي
he still has a conscience.
لا يزال لديه ضمير
I believe
أعتقد
he can change.
يمكنه أن يتغير
Are you here to force me to be Yang too?
هل أنت هنا إجباري على أن أكون يانغ أيضا؟
I hope you will,
آمل أن تفعل ذلك
but I won't force you.
لكنني لن أجبرك
Then what do you want?
إذن ماذا تريد؟
To laugh at me?
أن تضحك مني؟
Go ahead.
هيا
I, Wanyan...
أنا، وانيان...
No.
لا
I, Yang...
أنا، يانغ...
I've lived 18 years,
لقد عشت 18 عاما
not knowing who I am.
بدون معرفة من أنا
You don't need to struggle.
لست بحاجة إلى النضال
Our Yang family is loyal.
عائلتنا يانغ وفية
My foster father Yang Tiexin
والدي الكفيل يانغ تيهشين
was a real stand-up hero,
كان بطلا أماميا حقيقيا
daring to love and hate.
يجب أن تحبي وتكره
You can't even endure this.
لا يمكنك حتى تحمل هذا
You don't have any of his blood.
ليس لديك أي من دمه
You came here
جئت إلى هنا
just to humiliate me?
فقط لإذانتي؟
You did it.
أنت فعلت ذلك
Satisfied?
هل أنت راض؟
Why are you still here?
لماذا لا تزالين هنا؟
If you don't want my company,
إذا كنت لا تريد شركتي
just go back.
عد فحسب
The snow will get heavier,
الثلوج سوف تزداد أثقل
you'll catch a cold.
ستصابين بالزكام
I came to see you for my parents.
جئت لرؤيتك من أجل والديّ
They'd want you
سيريدونك
to live well.
أن تعيش حياة جيدة
It's not your business.
إنه ليس من شأنك
Masters.
سيد
Your Uncle Yang's funeral
جنازة عمك يانغ
is done.
انتهت
We've called you here
لقد اتصل بك هنا
to discuss something with you.
لمناقشة شيء معك
What is it?
ما هو؟
Your Uncle Yang's dying wish
أمنية عمك يانغ المحتضرة
was for you
كانت لك
to marry Miss Mu.
للزواج من الآنسة مو
Do you remember?
هل تتذكر؟
Yes.
نعم
But I can't marry her.
لكنني لا أستطيع الزواج منها
It's the last wish of your father
إنها آخر أمنية لأبيك
and Uncle Yang.
وعمي يانغ
Will you
هل ستفعل ذلك
go against it?
يعارض؟
It’s not Jing's fault.
هذا ليس خطأ جينغ
When we were in the desert,
عندما كنا في الصحراء
we got a letter
حصلنا على رسالة
from Zhongnan Mountain that Mr. Yang had a son,
من جبل تشونغ نان أن السيد يانغ كان لديه ابن
so the betrothal
لذلك الخطوبة
was void.
كان لاغيا
So,
لذلك
Jing got engaged
تورط جينغ
in the desert.
في الصحراء
Genghis Khan of Mongolia
غينغيس خان من منغوليا
appointed him as the Gold Knife Prince Consort.
عينته كنيفي الذهب أمير القرين
You seek wealth and power,
وتسعى إلى الثروة والسلطة
forget your roots and show ingratitude,
وتنسي جذورك وتظهر عدم الامتنان
no better than
لا أفضل من
Wanyan Kang!
وانيان كانغ!
I won't marry Princess Huazheng.
لن أتزوج الأميرة هواجنغ
Why?
لماذا؟
I see her as a sister,
فهمت كأخت
a good friend,
وصديقة جيدة
not a wife.
وليس زوجة
Good boy,
صبي صغير
you have your moral integrity
لديك سلامتك المعنوية
and ambition.
وطموحك
We don't have to
ليس علينا
care about the Khan
تهتم بخان
or the princess.
أو الأميرة
Just follow Uncle Yang's last wish,
فقط اتبعي أمنية العم يانغ الأخيرة
and marry Miss Mu.
وأتزوج الآنسة مو
I can't marry Miss Mu.
لا أستطيع زواج الآنسة مو
Jing,
جينغ
tell us.
أخبرنا
Is there someone else you love?
هل هناك شخص آخر تحبينه؟
Who is it?
من هو؟
Jing, tell us.
جينغ، أخبرنا
Which girl is it?
أي فتاة؟
Jing, tell us. Who is it?
جينغ، أخبرنا، من هي؟
It's Rong.
إنه رونغ
Rong?
دونغ؟
Rong who?
من؟
It's Huang Rong.
إنه هوانغ رونغ
The girl in white
الفتاة باللون الأبيض
at Prince Zhao's Mansion that day?
في حفل الأمير تشاو في ذلك اليوم؟
Exactly.
بالضبط
The girl who saved Mei Chaofeng?
الفتاة التي أنقذت مي تشاوفنغ؟
Jing,
جينغ
did you stop me from killing Mei Chaofeng
هل منعتني من قتل مي تشاوفنغ
because of her?
بسببها؟
I heard Mei called her junior sister
سمعت أن مي اتصلت بأختها الصغيرة
and her father master.
ووالدها ماهر
Isn't she Old Heretic Huang's daughter?
أليست ابنة هوانغ القديمة؟
That's right.
هذا صحيح
You want to marry Old Heretic Huang's daughter?
تريد أن تتزوج ابنة هوانغ القديمة؟
I've never met her father.
لم أقابل والدها أبدا
I don't know who he is.
لا أعرف من هو
So, you made a private vow?
إذن، هل أجرت تعهدا خاصا؟
No, we didn't.
لا لم نفعل
But I know my heart belongs to Rong
لكنني أعرف أن قلبي ملك رونغ
and hers to me.
وشأنها لي
We both know it.
كلانا يعرف ذلك
Jing,
جينغ
her father
والدها
is a cold-blooded
هو قاتل
killer.
قاتل
If he finds out
إذا اكتشف أنك
you're with his daughter secretly,
أنت مع ابنته سرا
you'll die!
ستموتين!
Mei Chaofeng has only a fraction of his skill,
مي تشاوفنغ ليس لديه سوى جزء من مهارته
and she's formidable.
وهي ضخمة
If he wants to kill you,
إذا أراد قتلك
who can save you?
من يستطيع إنقاذك؟
Rong is nice.
رونغ لطيف
Her father can't be so bad.
لا يمكن لوالدها أن يكون سيئا جدا
Nonsense!
هراء
Old Heretic Huang is pure evil.
هوانغ الحيلي القديم هو شر بحت
He is bad.
إنه سيء
You must swear
يجب أن تقسم
never
أبدا
to see
ألا أرى
that demoness again.
تلك الشيطان مرة أخرى
Swear it!
أقسم ذلك!
Never see her again！
لا أراها مرة أخرى
Jing.
جينغ
Sweat it.
تعرق
- Jing. - Say it.
- جينغ - لم ينجح
Jing.
جينغ
Be quick.
كن سريعا
You truly treat me well.
أنت تعاملني بشكل جيد حقا
No matter if I'm a man or a woman,
لا يهم إذا كنت رجلا أو امرأة
ugly or beautiful,
قبيحة أو جميلة
you'll always treat me well.
ستعاملني دائما بشكل جيد
Of course.
بالطبع
Master.
معلمي
I can't do it.
لا أستطيع فعل ذلك
What?
ماذا؟
Out in the world,
في العالم
dare you defy your masters?
هل تجرئين على تحدي سيادتك؟
Big brother.
أخ كبير
Big brother, calm down.
أخي الأكبر، اهدأ
Jing, stop angering your master.
جينغ، توقف عن غضب سيدك
- Say it! - Jing.
- قل ذلك! - جينغ
Good boy. Listen to your master.
صبي جيد، استمع إلى سيدك
Don't upset your masters.
لا تنزعج سيادتك
Jing.
جينغ
Swear it!
أقسم ذلك!
Who?
من؟
Why do you force him like this?
لماذا تجبره هكذا؟
Shame on you.
عار عليك
Jing,
جينغ
come out.
اخرج
Rong.
رونغ
- Jing... - Jing!
- جينغ... - جينغ!
Rong,
دونغ
thay are my masters.
تاي هم سيادي
I heard them forcing you,
سمعت أنهم يجبروك
and got angry.
وأغضب
You demoness!
أنت شيطان!
Master,
معلمي
Rong is not a demoness.
رونغ ليس شيطان
If I say she is, then she is.
إذا قلت أنها كذلك فهي كذلك
That's because you're blind.
هذا لأنك أعمى
You can't tell who's good
لا يمكنك معرفة من هو الجيد
- and who's the demoness. - You...
- ومن هي الشيطان - أنت...
You demoness!
أيها الأشقياء!
Am I right?
أنا على حق؟
You're so old.
كبرت جدًا
Can't you think of something new?
ألا يمكنك التفكير في شيء جديد؟
And you,
وأنت
nonsense show-off scholar,
هراء العالم
why did you insult my father
لماذا أهنت والدي
saying he's a cold-blooded killer?
قائلا إنه قاتل بارد؟
I don't argue with a girl.
لا أتشاجر مع فتاة
Don't be rude.
لا تكن فظًا
They're my masters.
إنهن سيدي
Fine, I will stop.
حسنًا، سأتوقف
Jing, come here.
جينغ، تعالي إلى هنا
I have a secret to tell you.
لدي سر لأخبرك به
Don't go!
لا تذهبي!
Jing,
جينغ
come here.
تعالي إلى هنا
Don't you go!
لا تذهب!
Jing.
جينغ
- Jing.
- جينغ
Jing!
جينغ!
Jing, come here.
جينغ، تعالي إلى هنا
Rong!
دونغ!
Jing! Jing!
جينغ!
Rong,
دونغ
where are we going?
إلى أين نحن ذاهبون؟
Get out of here
اخرجا من هنا
and go far away!
وابتعد!
My masters will be angry.
سيكون سيادي غاضبا
Aren't you afraid I'll be angry?
ألست خائفا من أنني سأكون غاضبة؟
♪Stars and the moon over the wild expanse♪
♪ النجوم والقمر فوق التوسع البري ♪
♪Longbows shooting toward the distant sun♪
♪ أرامل طويلة تطلق نحو الشمس البعيدة ♪
♪We meet in mountains and rivers♪
♪ نلتقي في الجبال والأنهار ♪
♪Rushing through narrow paths♪
♪ التحرك عبر مسارات ضيقة ♪
♪I wander through the martial world♪
♪ تتجول في عالم القتال ♪
♪All glitz mere illusions♪
♪ كل ألفاظ بسيطة ♪
♪Cutting off all debts♪
♪ إلغاء جميع الديون ♪
Jing,
جينغ
your masters wanted you
سيادتك أرادك
to marry Miss Mu
للزواج من الآنسة مو
or the Mongolian princess.
أو الأميرة المنغولية
Why did you refuse?
لماذا رفضت؟
Aren't they good enough?
أليست جيدة بما فيه الكفاية؟
They're good.
إنهما جيدان
But I can't marry them.
لكنني لا أستطيع الزواج منهما
Why?
لماذا؟
Miss Mu
الآنسة مو
is a beautiful
جميلة
girl.
فتاة
Even if you don't marry her,
حتى لو لم تتزوجها
you can also be a Gold Knife Prince Consort,
يمكنك أيضا أن تكون قرينة الأمير القرين من الذهب
with riches and glory.
بالثروات والمجد
Rong,
دونغ
just now,
للتو
I meant what I said
قصدت ما قلته
to my masters.
لأسيادي
- I only want... - Want what?
- أريد فقط... - وماذا تريدين؟
♪Or lost in the dust♪
♪ أو خسر في الغبار ♪
I only want to be with you.
أريد فقط أن أكون معك
I will never like anyone else.
لن أُعجب أبدا بأي شخص آخر
Me too.
أنا أيضًا
Rong.
رونغ
I'll take your hand
سآخذ يدك
and tell my masters
وأخبر سادي
and Taoist Ma
وتاويست ما
that Rong is not a demoness.
أن رونغ ليست شيطان
She is...
إنها...
She is a good,
إنها فتاة جيدة
good girl.
فتاة جيدة
Just good?
فتاة جيدة؟
Anything else?
أي شيء آخر؟
Just good.
جيد فقط
Rong,
دونغ
no one's better than you.
لا أحد أفضل منك
But your masters hate me.
لكن سيادتك يكرهونني
That won't help.
هذا لن يفيدي
Don't go back.
لا عد
Let's live in the mountains,
دعنا نعيش في الجبال
on an island,
على جزيرة
where they can't find us.
حيث لا يمكنهم العثور علينا
We can live there forever.
يمكننا العيش هناك إلى الأبد
But we've done nothing wrong.
لكننا لم نارتكب أي خطأ
Why do we need to hide?
لماذا علينا أن نختبئ؟
They'll tear us apart.
سوف تمزقنا
If we go back,
إذا عدنا
we won't see each other anymore.
لن نرى بعضنا البعض بعد الآن
No, Rong.
لا يا رونغ
I'd rather die
من الأفضل أن أموت
than be apart from you.
على أن أكون بعيدا عنك
Good.
جيد
We'll never be apart.
لن نكون منفصلين أبدا
With your words,
بكلماتك
I won't be afraid
لن أشعر بالخوف
of your masters.
من سيادتك
So,
لذلك
Rong,
رونغ
let's go find my masters.
دعنا نذهب ونجد سيادي
Then I'll go talk to Miss Mu
إذن سأذهب للتحدث إلى الآنسة مو
then go to the desert to break off the engagement.
إذن اذهب إلى الصحراء لكسر الخطوبة
Great.
عظيم
I'll follow your lead.
سأتبع خطاك
Masters!
سادة!
My masters must be angry with me
يجب أن يكون سيادي غاضبا مني
and left.
وغادر
Jing,
جينغ
don't worry.
لا تقلق
Remember?
تذكر؟
Your masters had a date with Wanyan Honglie.
كان سيادتك في موعد مع وانيان هونغليه
They'll meet at the Zuixian Restaurant in Jiaxing half a year later.
سيلتقون في مطعم زويكسيان في جيازينغ بعد نصف عام
We can go there to meet them.
يمكننا الذهاب إلى هناك للقاء بهم
We'll say something nice,
سنقول شيئا لطيفا
and they won't be mad.
ولن يكونوا غاضبين
I guess that's all we can do.
أظن أن هذا كل ما يمكننا فعله
(18 years ago)
(قبل 18 عاما)
(Ge Hill by the West Lake)
(جي هيل على البحيرة الغربية)
(is a sacred place of Taoism where Ge Hong practiced alchemy)
(هو مكان مقدس من الطاوية حيث تمارس جي هونغ الفن)
(during the Jin Dynasty.)
(خلال حداد جين)
(18 years ago,)
(قبل 18 عاما)
(I was sent here by my senior Ma Yu)
(تم إرسالي إلى هنا من قبل كبير ما يو)
(to study Taoist scriptures)
(لدراسة الكتب التاجية)
(and cultivate my character)
(وزراعة شخصيتي)
(because of my heavy hostility.)
(بسبب عدواني الثقيل)
(But then, I heard tragic news.)
(ولكن إذن، سمعت أخبار مأساوية)
Master, something went wrong.
معلمي، هناك خطب ما
Guo Xiaotian
قوه شياوتيان
and Yang Tiexin
ويانغ تيهشين
kindly invited me for a drink,
يرجى مني مشروبا
but
ولكن
they died because of me.
ماتوا بسببي
Where is that bloody official?
أين ذلك المسؤول الدموي؟
(Fahua Temple)
(معبد فهوا)
I pursued them relentlessly
تابعتها دون هوادة
and finally learned
وتعلمت أخيرا
that the villain Duan Tiande
أن دال تيانده الشريرة
had hidden Li,
قد أخف لي
Guo's pregnant wife
زوجة غو الحامل
in Fahua Temple.
في معبد فهوا
Stop!
توقف!
Taoist Qiu,
تاي تشيو
even if you want to make a name in Jiangnan,
حتى لو كنت ترغبين في كتابة اسم في جيانغنان
you can't disturb the peace of a Buddhist temple.
لا يمكنك الإخلال بسلام معبد بوذي
Shame on the place of peace!
عار على مكان السلام!
Can the monks hide
هل يمكن للرهبان أن يختبئوا
the widow of my good friend
أرملة صديقتي الجيدة
in your temple?
في معبد الخاص بك؟
You're slandering us
أنت تشهير بنا
(Reverend Jiaomu) and defaming our temple's reputation!
(الأب جياومو) وتشهير بسمعة معبد لنا!
Do you dare let me
هل تجرؤ على السماح لي
search your temple?
ابحث في معبد الخاص بك؟
If you don't release her today,
إذا لم تفرج عنها اليوم
I'll burn
سأحرق
this Fahua Temple down.
معبد الفهوا هذا
Taoist, you rely on your martial arts prowess,
طاوي، أنت تعتمد على براءتك في فنون الدفاع عن النفس
pursue fame and wealth,
من أجل الشهرة والثروة
and align with the Jin.
ومواءمة مع جين
Now you chase our Song generals to here.
الآن تطاردون جنرالات الأغنية إلى هنا
How can our Fahua Temple
كيف يمكن لمعبد الناهوا
tolerate you
يتغاضى عنك
using loyal lives
باستخدام الأرواح المخلصة
to curry favor
لكتابة المعروف
with the Jin?
مع جين؟
Qiu Chuji.
تشوجي
We Seven Freaks of Jiangnan
نحن السبع من جيانغنان
won't let you have your way here!
لن يسمح لك الطريق إلى هنا!
(Only later did I learn)
(لم أتعلم إلا بعد ذلك)
(that Duan Tiande had falsely accused me)
(أن دوان تيانده قد اتهمني زورا)
(to Reverend Jiaomu)
(للأب جياومو)
(and the Seven Freaks of Jiangnan.)
و(مقاطعات جيانغنان السبعة)
(So we had a misunderstanding.)
(لذلك كان لدينا سوء فهم)
(Both I and the seven heroes)
(أنا والأبطال السبعة)
(were badly injured in the end.)
(أصيبوا بجروح بليغة في النهاية)
Let me go!
اتركني!
Go!
هيا!
Why is there a woman's voice?
لماذا صوت امرأة؟
Taoist Qiu!
طاوية تشي يو!
I'm Guo Xiaotian's wife.
أنا زوجة غو شياوتيان
Please save me!
أرجوك أنقذني!
Be quiet!
اصمت!
Think about your unborn child!
فكّر في طفلك الذي لم يولد بعد!
It really is a woman.
إنها امرأة حقًا
A woman
امرأة
is hidden in the Fahua Temple.
مختبئة في معبد فهوا
Oh, no.
لا
Now, we Seven Freaks of Jiangnan
الآن، نحن كتائب السبع من جيانغنان
will be known as the Seven Demons of Jiangnan.
سيعرف باسم شيطان جيانغنان السبعة
Being called seven fools
يطلق عليهم سبعة حمقى
in the martial world
في عالم القتال
wouldn't be an exaggeration.
لن يكون مبالغة
Jiaomu!
جياومو!
You misjudged people.
لقد أخطأت في الحكم على الناس
You almost got us killed!
كدت أن تقتلنا!
Darn it.
اللعنة!
You wretched Taoist!
أيها الطايع البغيض!
Good for you.
هنيئًا لك
I can't mess with you.
لا أستطيع الفوضى معك
I'll just avoid you.
سأتجنبك فحسب
So, I'll take my leave.
لذا سأغادر
Go!
اذهبي!
Reverend,
مرحبًا
you really don't have to do this.
أنت حقا ليس عليك القيام بذلك
Listen to me.
اسمعوا إليّ
Let me go!
اتركني
Mr. Duan,
السيد دوان
don't do this!
لا تفعل هذا!
Reverend,
تعال
if you don't stop,
إذا لم تتوقف
I'll have no choice but to kill you.
لن يكون لدي خيار سوى قتلك
You'll feel pain
ستشعر بالألم
when I stab you.
عندما أطعنك
Go away.
ابتعد
Go!
هيا!
Aren't you afraid of retribution
ألا تخافين من العقاب
for all your sins?
لكل ذكائك؟
Go!
اذهب!
Taoist!
طاوي!
(Zuixian Restaurant) Taoist Qiu, we are
(مطعم Zuixian) تاي تشيو، نحن آسفون حقا
truly sorry for today.
آسف حقا على اليوم
It was my carelessness that allowed
كان عدم ملكي هو الذي سمح
that scoundrel
ذلك الحيلة
to take advantage.
للاستفادة
So, what should we do now?
لذلك، ماذا علينا أن نفعل الآن؟
Let's settle it.
دعنا نقوم بتسويتها
Today's event
حدث اليوم
is a disgrace
هو خيانة
to both sides.
لكلا الجانبين
If we don't rescue
إذا لم ننتقم
the widows of the Guo and the Yang,
أرامل الغو واليانغ
how can we face
كيف يمكن أن نواجه
the martial world?
عالم القتال؟
Well said.
قل جيدا
So what do you suggest?
فماذا تقترح الآن؟
Now that Mrs. Guo and Mrs. Yang
بما أن السيدة غو والسيدة يانغ
were taken by them.
أخذوه
Let's split up
دعنا نقسم
to rescue them.
لإنقاذهم
We met Li,
التقينا لي
Mrs. Guo today.
السيدة غو اليوم
I won't forget
لن أنسى صوت السيدة غو
Mrs. Guo's voice.
صوت السيدة غو
So,
لذلك
we'll go find Mrs. Guo.
سنذهب للعثور على السيدة غو
Good.
جيد
Then I'll go find Mrs. Yang.
إذن سأذهب للعثور على السيدة يانغ
Shall we compete to see
هل نتنافس لرؤية
who rescues first?
من ينقذ أولا؟
Let's save them first.
دعنا ننقذه أولا
After Mrs. Guo and Mrs. Yang
بعد السيدة غو والسيدة يانغ
give birth,
عند الولادة
we will
سنقوم
teach the babies all we know.
علّم الأطفال كل ما نعرفه
18 years later,
بعد 18 سنة
we'll bring the children of Guo and Yang
سنحضر أولادي غو ويانغ
back to Zuixian Restaurant
إلى مطعم زويكسيان
for a duel. Okay?
لمثول مدين، اتفقنا؟
Okay.
حسنًا
We accept it.
نحن نقبل ذلك
Heroes, we will
الأبطال، سوف
take off soon.
سنبدأ قريبا
(18 years later)
(بعد 18 سنة)
Today, let's
اليوم، دعنا
settle the duel
تسوية الدويل
from 18 years ago today.
من قبل 18 عاما اليوم
Luckily,
لحسن الحظ
I can have my two seniors
يمكنني الحصول على رئيسي السن
as witnesses.
كشهود
What do you say?
ماذا تقول؟
I agree.
أوافقك الرأي
If not
إذا لم يكن الأمر كذلك
for your righteous help,
لمساعدتك الصالحة
my senior brothers and I
أنا وأخوتي
would not have survived.
لم أكن لأبقى على قيد الحياة
Your apprentice, Guo Jing,
تلميذك، قوه
he
هو
excels in martial arts,
يتفوق في فنون الدفاع عن النفس
and also possesses a noble spirit.
ويتمتع أيضا بروح نبيلة
What a man of integrity!
يا له من رجل مسؤول!
Exactly.
بالضبط
Thanks to Jing for finding the antidote for me.
بفضل جينغ لإيجاد الترياق لي
As for my evil apprentice Yang Kang,
أما بالنسبة إلى تلميذي الأشرار يانغ كانغ
he is morally corrupt,
فاسد أخلاقيا
and greedy for fame and fortune.
والجشعة من أجل الشهرة والثروة
He's nowhere near
إنه بعيدة كل البعد عن
as good as Guo Jing.
جيد مثل غو جينغ
Now, I concede defeat
الآن، أعترف بالهزيمة
in the duel we promised 18 years ago
في الدمية التي وعدناها قبل 18 سنة
at the Zuixian Restaurant.
في مطعم زويشيان
Taoist, that's very nice of you.
طاوي، هذا لطيف منك
We haven't done much better
لم نفعل أفضل كثيرا
at teaching our apprentice.
في تعليم تلميذنا
Guo Jing, that rascal,
قوه جينغ، ذلك الوغد
he dared...
تجرأ...
He dared to defy his masters
تجرأ على تحدي ساده
for that demoness from Peach Blossom Island
عن تلك الشيطان من جزيرة زهر الخوخ
and eloped with her.
هربت معها
Big brother,
أخي الكبير
why do you still
لماذا ما زلت
hold a grudge over this?
تحمل ضغينة على هذا؟
Hero Ke,
البطل تشي
don't worry.
لا تقلق
Jing is an honest and loyal man.
جينغ هو رجل صادق ومخلص
If he's too obedient
إذا كان مطيعا جدا
to masters and seniors,
للأسياد وكبار السن
he won't have any independent opinions.
لن يكون لديه أي آراء مستقلة
Now,
الآن
he has his own choice.
لديه اختياره الخاص
Perhaps it's a good thing.
ربما هذا أمر جيد
Big brother,
أخي الكبير
I think Taoist Ma is correct.
أعتقد أن تاي ما على حق
We've been
لقد كنا
a bit hard on Jing.
على جينغ
Everyone.
الجميع
As far as I can tell,
بقدر ما أستطيع أن أقول
Huang Rong truly cares
هوانغ رونغ يهتم حقا
for Jing.
لجينغ
That girl
تلك الفتاة
really likes Jing.
حقا تحب جينغ
And Jing will never
وجينغ لن
like any other girls
مثل أي فتيات أخريات
besides her.
إلى جانبها
Congratulations to you all.
تهانيّ لكم جميعا
Your apprentice
تلميذك
finally will finish his apprenticeship.
سوف ينهي تدريبه أخيرا
Since that's the case,
وبما أن هذا هو الحال
I will
سأكون
let him be this time.
دعه يكون هذه المرة
There you go.
ها أنت ذي
- Your Highness!
- صاحب السمو!
Your Highness!
سموك!
- Your Highness.
- صاحب السمو
We've finally found you.
وجدكما أخيرا
Please go back with us.
أرجوك عد معنا
- His Royal Highness is worried about you. - Yes, Your Highness.
- صاحب السمو الملكي قلق عليك - نعم يا صاحب السمو
I'm not a prince. Stay back.
أنا لست أميرا، ابتعد
- Your Highness.
- صاحب السمو
Get lost!
اغرب عن وجهي!
- Yes. - Your Highness.
- نعم - صاحب السمو
Fragrant bags! Pendants!
أكياس عشب! بندر!
Umbrellas!
مظلات!
Do you like it?
هل يعجبك؟
I've never had it before.
لم أحبها من قبل
But it tastes good.
لكنه شهي مذاقه
Father said
أبي قال
Mother used to cook the noodles
كانت الأم تطبخ النودلز
for him.
نيابة عنه
For these 18 years,
لهذه السنوات الـ 18
Mother longed for such a life.
أمي تتطلع إلى مثل هذه الحياة
I don't understand.
أنا لا أفهم
If it were you,
إذا كنت أنت
would you choose to be a princess
هل ستختار أن تكوني أميرة
or go back to the Niujia Village?
أو عد إلى قرية نيوجيا؟
I'll go back to the Niujia Village.
سأعود إلى قرية نيوجيا
And I won't come to
ولن آتي إلى
Zhongdu anymore.
تشونغ دو بعد الآن
This is my father's iron spear.
هذا رمح والدي من الحديد
I'll give it to you as a keepsake.
سأعطيها لك كتذكار
(Yang Tiexin)
(يانغ تييكسين)
How did you find me?
كيف وجدتني؟
Anyway,
على أية حال
I can find you if I want to.
يمكنني العثور عليك إذا أردت ذلك
Will you marry Guo Jing?
هل ستتزوج غوو جينغ؟
I won't.
لن أفعل
But Father betrothed you
لكن الأب خطيبك
to Guo Jing before he died.
إلى غوو جينغ قبل أن مات
He won't marry me.
لن يتزوجني
And I won't marry him.
ولن أتزوجه
Why?
لماذا؟
He loves someone else.
إنه يحب شخصا آخر
Besides,
الى جانب ذلك
Father had betrothed me
كان الأب خطيبني
to someone else before.
لشخص آخر من قبل
To that
إلى ذلك
dandyish prince of Jin?
أمير جين الدموي؟
Not this wretch bullying his master,
ليس هذا البﻻء يتنمر على معلمه
betraying his ancestors,
والخيانة على أسلافه
and not even knowing
ولا حتى يعرف
his family name!
اسمه العائلي!
I don't know any prince of Jin.
لا أعرف أي أمير جين
I only know Yang Kang, a man
أعرف فقط يانغ كانغ، رجل
with a tragic past and a deep-seated vendetta.
لديه ماض مفجع وانتقام عميق
Father had betrothed me
كان الأب خطبني
to him.
له
I don't have parents.
ليس لدي آباء
Don't abandon me.
لا تتخلى عني
♪My heart hastens to the peach blossom garden♪
♪ قلبي يستعد إلى حديقة زهر الخوخ ♪
♪Heading toward a distant abyss♪
♪ استمع نحو هاوية بعيدة ♪
♪Dreaming of one day falling into your embrace♪
♪ أحلم بيوم واحد سقط في عناقك ♪
No.
لا
I can't do this.
لا يمكنني فعل هذا
Though I'm a poor girl
على الرغم من أنني فتاة فقيرة
wandering in the martial world,
في عالم القتال
I'm not
أنا لست
a hussy
صخب
who lacks self-respect.
من يفتقر إلى احترام الذات
If you truly love me,
إذا كنت تحبني حقا
you should respect me
يجب أن تحترمني
and cherish me.
والاعتناء بي
Then I won't love anyone else.
إذن لن أحب أي شخص آخر
Even if threatened with death,
حتى لو هُدد بالموت
I'll stay with you.
سأبقى معك
If one day,
إذا كان في يوم من الأيام
we can have a wedding night,
يمكننا أن نقيم ليلة زفاف
I will... I will do as you wish now.
سأفعل ما يحلو لك الآن
But today, if you want to dishonor me,
لكن اليوم، إن أردت أن تؤذيني
I'd rather die.
أفضل أن أموت
♪You are deeply rooted in my heart♪
♪ أنت متجذرة بعمق في قلبي ♪
Sister Mu.
أخت مو
Don't be angry.
لا تغضب
It was my fault.
كان ذلك خطأي
I'll be waiting for you at my foster father's home
سأكون في انتظارك في منزل والدي الكفيل
at the Niujia Village, Lin'an.
في قرية نيوجيا، لين آن
Please come to find me
من فضلك تعالي للعثور علي
with a proper matchmaker.
مع منسق مناسب
After I take care of these matters,
بعد أن أهتم بهذه الأمور
I'll go to marry you.
سأذهب للزواج منك
I won't betray you
لن أخونك
in this life.
في هذه الحياة
♪I won't give myself time to regret♪
♪ لن أعطي نفسي الوقت للأسف ♪
Rong,
رونغ
why did you buy so many things?
لماذا اشتريت الكثير من الأشياء؟
I grew up on the Peach Blossom Island.
ترعرعت على جزيرة برسوم الخوخ
I rarely see these things.
نادرا ما أرى هذه الأشياء
Now I'm finally come out of home
الآن أخيرًا أخرج من المنزل
with your company,
مع شركتك
I should have fun.
يجب أن أستمتع بوقتي
From now on, I'll buy you
من الآن فصاعدًا، سأشتري لك
whatever you like.
افعل ما يحلو لك
Good.
جيد
But you must also
لكن يجب عليك أيضا
join me to have fun.
انضمي لي للحصول على المرح
Of course.
بالطبع
Jing, have you played Cuju?
جينغ، هل لعبت دور الكرة؟
That's Gao Qiu's game. [*Gao Qiu: a well-known villain]
هذه هي لعبة قاو تشيو [* قاو تشيو: شرير معروف]
My ancestor is Guo Sheng, a hero of Liangshan.
أسلافي هو غو شنغ، بطل ليانغشان
So I won't play that.
لذلك لن أعزف على ذلك
Gao Qiu is evil, but is Cuju?
قاو تشيو شر، لكن هل تشيو؟
I want you to play with me.
أريدك أن تلعب معي
Sir.
سيدي
Are you alright?
هل أنت بخير؟
Leave me alone.
دعني وشأني
(Hong Qi, Northern Beggar)
(هونغ تشي، الحظيرة الشمالية)
Kids, what are you playing?
يا أولاد، ماذا تلعب؟
Cuju?
الكرة؟
It's disturbing my nap.
إنه مزعج بالنسبة لي
Go play elsewhere.
اذهب للعب في مكان آخر
Did you plant this tree?
هل زرعت هذه الشجرة؟
Why can you sleep here,
لماذا يمكنك النوم هنا
but we can't play Cuju?
لكننا لا نستطيع لعب الكرة؟
So stroppy.
لذا استرجعنا
Rong, it's our fault.
رونغ، إنه خطؤنا
Let's go.
لنذهب
How about this.
ماذا عن هذا
Let's play Cuju.
دعنا نلعب الكرة
Who wins
من يفوز
gets the tree.
تحصل على الشجرة
Okay.
حسنًا
So,
لذلك
how do we decide the winner?
كيف نقرر الفائز؟
Stick your pole in the ground.
ضع قطبك في الأرض
Who hits it wins.
من يضرب بجذوره يفوز
Deal.
اتفقنا
Jing, you go first.
جينغ، اذهب أولا
Sir, you go first.
سيدي، اذهب أولا
You go first!
اذهبي أولا!
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
♪I wander in the martial world♪
♪ أتجول في عالم القتال ♪
♪I drink a thousand cups of wine and sing to the sky♪
♪ أشرب ألف كوب من النبيذ والغناء إلى السماء ♪
♪Life and death intertwined♪
♪ الحياة والموت متشابكين ♪
♪Leaning against the railing and shouting♪
♪ الوقوف ضد الغرق والنار ♪
♪Stars and moon over the wild expanse♪
♪ النجوم والقمر فوق التوسع البري ♪
♪Longbows shooting toward the distant sun♪
♪ أصوات طويلة تطلق نحو الشمس البعيدة ♪
♪We meet in mountains and rivers♪
♪ نلتقي في الجبال والأنهار ♪
♪Rushing through narrow paths♪
♪ التحرك عبر مسارات ضيقة ♪
♪I wander through the martial world♪
♪ تتجول في عالم القتال ♪
♪All glitz mere illusions♪
♪ كل ألفاظ بسيطة ♪
♪Cutting off all debts♪
♪ إلغاء جميع الديون ♪
♪Only the shadows of swords and gleaming blades can be seen♪
♪ فقط ظلال السيوف والشفرات الكاذبة يمكن رؤيتها ♪
♪Fearless, undaunted♪
♪ لا خوف ولا مهرب ♪
♪The marial world is a lifetime of daring♪
♪ العالم الملكي هو حياة من الجرأة ♪
♪Who knows my dreams and ambitions♪
♪ من يعرف أحلامي وطموحاتي ♪
♪Wakening to find them as distant dreams♪
♪ الاستيقاظ للعثور عليهم كأحلام بعيدة ♪
♪The road ahead is long♪
♪ الطريق إلى الأمام طويل ♪
♪The path is vast and grand♪
♪ الطريق شاسع ودقيق ♪
♪Thousands of dreams span ages♪
♪ بآلاف الأحلام تمتد عبر الأعمار ♪
♪Whirling and swirling♪
♪ الحيلة والسباحة ♪
♪Ask the youth what it means♪
♪ اطلب من الشباب ما يعنيه ♪
♪Heroes face all challenges♪
♪ الأبطال يواجهون جميع التحديات ♪
♪True to their hearts♪
♪ أرغب في قلوبهم ♪
♪Or lost in the dust♪
♪ أو خسر في الغبار ♪
♪The road ahead is long♪
♪ الطريق إلى الأمام طويل ♪
♪The path is vast and grand♪
♪ الطريق شاسع وغالي ♪
♪People in the world varied and numerous♪
♪ الناس في العالم متنوعون وعديدون ♪
♪Whirling and swirling♪
♪ الحيلة والسباحة ♪
♪Who truly understands♪
♪ من يفهم ♪ حقا
♪Heroes face all challenges♪
♪ الأبطال يواجهون جميع التحديات ♪
♪Searching to truly grasp♪
♪ ابحث عن فهم ♪ حقا
♪Only then do they discern♪
♪ إذن لا يتلاحظوا ♪
♪Achievements and mistakes are transient♪
♪ الإنجازات والأخطاء عابرة ♪
♪To the end, yet steps persist♪
♪ حتى النهاية، لكن الخطوات لا تزال مستمرة ♪
♪We can feel pain and also joy♪
♪ يمكننا أن نشعر بالألم والسعادة ♪
♪We can charge forward or retreat♪
♪ يمكننا أن نتراجع للأمام ♪
♪No need to look back♪
♪ لا داعي للنظر إلى الوراء ♪
♪Rush through wind and clouds, shake the universe♪
♪ مرور الرياح والسحب، تهز الكون ♪
♪No matter the journey's length♪
♪ لا يهم طول الرحلة ♪
♪Entering the martial world♪
♪ دخول عالم القتال ♪
♪I fear not the endless journey♪
♪ لا أخشى الرحلة التي لا نهاية لها ♪